Bex Ford | Junior Front-End Developer

Email: becky782@hotmail.co.uk

Mobile: 07557361414

GitHub: github.com/bex-ford LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/bex-ford

Professional Profile

Motivated graduate Front-End Developer with knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and React programming languages. Passion for learning and developing my knowledge in Software Development. I am a extremely motivated person and give my all to my work. I have fantastic organisation and communication skills which I have developed during my career as a Orthodontic Therapist.

I have worked in Dentistry for a little over 12 years where my communication skills have really excelled. Working with the general public and fellow members of staff in a intense setting has gained me with great confidence in communication, patience and the ability to prepare for the unexpected. My passion for Software Development has made me want to pursue this as a full time career therefor I have completed courses whilst working full time to make this happen.

Core Skills

- HTML
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- React

Career Summary

Code First Girls Data & SQL

Commencing March 27th 2023 - May 2023

edX Skills for life Front-End Development

November 2022 - March 2023

Graduated March 2023

Whilst working full time I completed this bootcamp which involved 4 night classes 6pm-9am alongside at least 15 hours of coursework and self study per week. I gained a lot of knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, React and GitHub. We had weekly assignments and challenges to complete. This bootcamp was incredibly intense, fast paced and extremely rewarding.

Coding Traineeship

2021 - 2022

IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship – Full stack developer 1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills.

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Orthodontic Therapy

2016 - 2023

Dean Road Dental Practice Orthodontic Therapist

- Extremely versatile, hardworking and dedicated to the role
- A high standard of organisation, preparing for each day
- Worked with both NHS and private patients, working alongside and under the prescription of an orthodontist

 Worked with removable appliances, fixed appliances and Invisalign treatments

2011 – 2016 Dean Road Dental Practice

Orthodontic Nurse

May 2019 – 2021 Queensway Orthodontic Practice

Orthodontic Therapist

Mar 2008 – 2011 Silver & Charlton Dental Practice

Dental Nurse

2007 – 2010 Warehouse Fashions

Sales Advisor

Education

edX Front-End Development Bootcamp 2022-2023

Graduated

IT Career Switch Ltd 2021-2022

Coding Traineeship - Full stack developer

UCLan 2016-2017

Diploma in Orthodontic Therapy (Grade: Gold Medal)

BDA 2015-2016

Radiography Qualified (Grade: B)

Durham Orthodontic Nursing 2013

Certificate in Orthodontic Dental Nursing (Grade: Pass)

North East Chamber of Commerce 2009-2011

NVQ Level 3 in Dental Nursing (Grade: Pass)

Seaham School of Technology 2002-2007

6 GCSEs A-C

Level 2 Adult Numeracy (Grade: Pass)

Volunteer Work

The People's Kitchen Newcastle. I helped serve food and ensured our vulnerable friends were provided with clothing and necessary toiletries.

Interests

- Gym
- Hiking
- Audiobooks
- Podcasts

References available on request